<article>old definition of ARTICLE s. m.
Small part or division of a speech, a writing, a memoir. St. Thomas divides his Summa into several questions, and each question into several articles. this account contains several articles in each chapter of receipt and expense. this memorandum of costs contained 200 articles. these three articles must be attached together.

ARTICLE, is also said of the clauses and conventions of Treaties and Judgments on which there are disputes and deliberations. We have already agreed on so many articles of the Treaty of Peace, articles of the capitulation. we have already judged three articles of this process. we have given articles of marriage; and we say absolutely, Sign articles, to say, Sign a marriage contract. We can have his party questioned on facts and articles that we notify him of.

ARTICLE OF FAITH, is said of all the points of Religion decided by the Councils, and which the Catholic, Apostolic, and Roman Church believes. The controversial articles are those which are debated by Heretics.

ARTICLE, also signifies, a particular thing. He was given a suit of clothes, and he still asks for a cloak; this is another article. He withdrew the furniture which he had pledged, but he found fault with several articles. All his property consists of one article, to say, in a house, in a piece of land. He is given all the furniture of this inventory in his custody, which was counted for him article by article.
ARTICLE, in terms of Medicine, signifies, a joint of the bones of the human body. Gout is a disease which comes in the articles, and is called Morbus articularis. It was discovered that this man was massacred by a Surgeon, because he was cut by articles. We also call Articles, the very things that are joined. Each part of which a body, a hand is composed, is an article.

THE ARTICLE OF DEATH, is the agony, the time when one is close to dying. This man has confessed everything at the article of death.

ARTICLE, in terms of Grammar, is a particle used by most Languages ​​to inflect nouns, and to mark their cases and their genders. The feminine, masculine article. the article of the singular, plural, nominative, dative, etc. Some make the article pass for a part of Oration; but it should rather be placed in the rank of pronouns.
ARTICLE, is said proverbially in these sentences. When a man has ruined himself in a short time, we say that he has eaten all his wealth in one article; & of a glutton who eats quickly, we say that when he holds a chicken, he makes only one article of it; & of a man who is confused, we say that he puts everything in one article, that he makes no distinction between things. We also say of a man of easy belief, that he believes everything that is told to him as an article of faith.
	This word comes from the Latin articulus, from artus.
</article>